# R. Winston Larson

winstonlarson@gmail.com 617.595.9353 winstonlarson.com

223 Concord Turnpike, #275 Cambridge, MA 02140

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am interested in combining my skills in data science, business, and engineering to build new products and businesses. Through a research-oriented mindset and hypothesis-driven approach, I have acquired extensive experience solving ambiguous problems. My diverse background in innovation strategy, R&D management, mechanical engineering, and industrial manufacturing enables me to understand complex problems and identify creative solutions. I specialize in building and executing R&D strategies under circumstances of high technical and market uncertainty.

### **EDUCATION**

## Massachusetts Institute of Technology

SM Mechanical Engineering, January 2014 - Major GPA: 5.0/5.0

Relevant coursework: Sustainable manufacturing, computer science and eng., innovation strategy, entrepreneurship.

#### Master's Thesis, 2012-2014 - MIT Presidential Fellow

Strategic and Financial Implications of Unmanned Underwater Vehicles and Long-term Underwater Power Sources.

SB Mechanical Engineering, June 2012 - GPA: 5.0/5.0

Relevant coursework: Manufacturing, systems engineering, product design & dev, robotics & controls, programming.

**Research projects:** Bio-mimetic underwater robotics, networked indoor robot navigation, firearms identification for Boston Police, compact fusion power for spacecraft

## **EXPERIENCE**

Innovation Consultant, Innosight 2014-2015

Assisting Fortune 500 companies to respond to disruptive innovation as an innovation consultant.

- Biotech computing: Managed the design of a cloud-based computational platform for biotech R&D
- Pharmaceutical R&D: Created new R&D accelerator and launched its first project at a major pharma.
- Energy & Water: Launched strategic initiative in water at an electric utility in California.
- Consumer Electronics: Devised R&D strategy for a new product line being launched by a consumer company.
- Semiconductor Manufacturing: Advised assessment and expansion of capabilities at an electronics company.
- Internet of things: Facilitated a symposium examining opportunities and challenges in the Industrial Internet

Unmanned Underwater Vehicle (UUV) Projects with Lincoln Laboratory, MIT 2011-2014

Managed research team members, experimental research, accounting (\$300k budget), procurement, and technical documentation & communication for prototype long-term underwater power sources. Founded a startup, competed in the MIT 100K, acted as CFO & COO.

#### **Boeing Company, Summer 2012**

Manufacturing and Robotics Engineering Intern

Contributed to the development of a revolutionary manufacturing line to improve aircraft quality & takt time, building & presenting critical industrial robotic vision & manipulation systems to upper management.

#### Schlumberger Limited, Summer 2011

Manufacturing Engineering Intern

Led a team to design, build, and implement apparati for testing electrical components for oil service equipment.

## SKILLS

**Technical:** Systems engineering; manufacturing; data mining and analysis; Python (pandas, Numpy, SciPy), Java & Matlab; SolidWorks; product design and development; electronics.

**Business:** Team & project management; strategy & business development; disruptive innovation; entrepreneurship & startups; communication, presentations & writing.